<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:sparkle="http://www.andymatuschak.org/xml-namespaces/sparkle" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Platypus Version Release Appcast</title>
        <link>https://sveinbjorn.org/files/appcasts/PlatypusAppcast.xml</link>
        <description>Most recent release list for Platypus, with links to updates.</description>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title>Version 5.4</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 3 Sep 2022 19:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://sveinbjorn.org/files/software/platypus/platypus5.4.zip" sparkle:version="1233" sparkle:shortVersionString="5.4" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:dsaSignature="MC0CFG9AmNyGBj3DZ1XoGIrPgN+Dpv8VAhUArZsbkDid6Z/Ed85+BUWf5yXC4Hg=" sparkle:edSignature="AoUtDC55R3afC3CN3/SQQJo+1wfkpxr+2EScWOWT/keDi5IUV0WfuCRR5qSD8G8f1fL8I/OIEapgmWjNvsndAQ==" length="4325671"
            />
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>10.11.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[
                <h2>Version 5.4</h2>
                <ul>
                    <li>Added native support for the arm64 CPU architecture (Apple Silicon). Both Platypus and the apps it generates are now Universal ARM/Intel 64-bit binaries</li>
                    <li>New application icon</li>
                    <li>Status Menu submenu items can now be disabled with the DISABLED syntax</li>
                    <li>Support relative interpreter path (i.e. relative to Resources directory)</li>
                    <li>Support dark mode for text fields (inverts colors, changes dynamically when user switches interface modes)</li>
                    <li>Command line tool no longer defaults to stripping nib file (requires explicit -y option)</li>
                    <li>Enabled close button on windows, which now quit the app(s)</li>
                    <li>Added standard Help Menu to ScriptExec apps (support for bundled help bundles)</li>
                    <li>Added support for dynamically changing status item title and icon via STATUSTITLE and STATUSICON syntax</li>
                    <li>Warn when non-existent file in bundled files list</li>
                    <li>Command line tool now defaults to creating apps with no application icon</li>
                    <li>Support for notifications is now an option, to prevent permission popups on Catalina and later</li>
                    <li>Added Python 3 and Dart interpreter presets</li>
                    <li>Platypus apps now hide (instead of disabling) Open and Open Recent menu items if they don't accept files</li>
                    <li>Fixed issue with signing generated apps due to missing "APPL" CFBundleType</li>
                    <li>Fixed nasty empty newline parsing bug</li>
                    <li>Switched over to AGIconFamily for icon generation, reducing dependence on deprecated Carbon calls</li>
                    <li>Resolved issue with text selection and dark mode in generated apps</li>
                    <li>Improved drag and drop handling on Platypus main window</li>
                    <li>Now requires macOS 10.11 or later</li>
                </ul>
            ]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
