<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:sparkle="http://www.andymatuschak.org/xml-namespaces/sparkle" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Platypus Version Release Appcast</title>
        <link>http://sveinbjorn.org/files/appcasts/PlatypusAppcast.xml</link>
        <description>Most recent release list for Platypus, with links to signed updates.</description>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title>Version 5.0</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 2 Apr 2015 15:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://sveinbjorn.org/files/software/platypus/platypus5.0.zip" sparkle:version="5.0" sparkle:shortVersionString="5.0" length="" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:dsaSignature=""/>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>10.7.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[
                <h2>Version 5.0 Changes</h2>
                <ul>
                    <li>This is a major update to Platypus with lots of new features</li>
                    <li>Modernised user interface with high-resolution icons and interface assets</li>
                    <li>Added support for Uniform Type Identifiers (UTIs) in Drop Settings</li>
                    <li>Added NOTIFICATION: syntax, which sends a notification to User Notification Center</li>
                    <li>Added ALERT: syntax, which triggers a modal alert dialog</li>
                    <li>Added MENUITEMICON: syntax, which sets menu item icon in status item menus</li>
                    <li>Dropped text input (NSPboardText) is now passed to script via STDIN, not as an argument. This allows differentiation between dropped text snippets and dropped files in applications that are made to handle both.</li>
                    <li>The built-in editor has been much enhanced, with line numbering, configurable text size, word wrap and other improvements</li>
                    <li>Parsed commands are now removed from script text output</li>
                    <li>Documentation completely overhauled and expanded</li>
                    <li>New "Use System Font" option for status menu items</li>
                    <li>Symlinks now resolved when adding files to Bundled Files list</li>
                    <li>Folder sizes are now calculated much faster (and asynchronously) when added to Bundled Files list</li>
                    <li>Arguments window now highlights arguments and argument groups in command preview field</li>
                    <li>Previewing status item menu now shows actual script output instead of placeholder text</li>
                    <li>Many new examples</li>
                    <li>Command line tool now supports --long-options</li>
                    <li>Author name argument is now used to generate default bundle identifier in command line tool</li>
                    <li>Finder now refreshes display of overwritten applications</li>
                    <li>Status menu items can now only have a title or an icon, not both, due to changes in Mac OS X</li>
                    <li>Show Shell Command window now shows install status of command line tool</li>
                    <li>Syntax checker window now shows the command invoked when checking script syntax</li>
                    <li>App size estimation is now more accurate</li>
                    <li>Font size in web output view can now also be increased/reduced</li>
                    <li>New contexual menu button for icon view</li>
                    <li>New "Copy icon path" option in icon contextual menu</li>
                    <li>Platypus-generated apps now remember font size set by user</li>
                    <li>Fixed issue with generating icon from images on retina macs (IconFamily)</li>
                    <li>Fixed issue with broken icon image alpha channels (IconFamily)</li>
                    <li>Fixed issue where a status item menu would display an empty menu if clicked repeatedly</li>
                    <li>Fixed issue where dropping text on an app wouldn't work with “Remain running after initial execution” off</li>
                    <li>Fixed issue with Open... menu item and file types in ScriptExec</li>
                    <li>Fixed issue where process number arguments in the format -psn_0_* were passed to script</li>
                    <li>Fixed issue where command line arguments for ScriptExec were being passed incorrectly to script</li>
                    <li>Many, many minor bugfixes, tweaks and improvements
                    <li>Codebase migrated to modern Objective-C syntax. Built with XCode 7 and now requires Mac OS X 10.7 or later and a 64-bit Intel system. Older versions continue to work just fine on 32-bit 10.6 systems, and version 4.4 still works on PowerPC. But it's time to leave the past behind. It's been 9 years since the last 32-bit Mac was released.</li>
                </ul>
            ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Version 4.9</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 2 Apr 2015 15:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://sveinbjorn.org/files/software/platypus/platypus4.9.zip" sparkle:version="4.9" sparkle:shortVersionString="4.9" length="1668252" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:dsaSignature="MC0CFCU9a7YtceYxs/6LIpqykQPKghTyAhUAs3SFJFKOn4fXzEy76S3qXVlwGUk="/>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>10.6.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[
                <h2>Version 4.9 Changes</h2>
                <ul>
                <li>Users can now manually increase/decrease the font size in Platypus-generated apps</li>
                <li>Status menu items can now be selected. This will run the script again with the menu title as an argument.</li>
                <li>Arguments can now be passed to Platypus-generated apps via the command line</li>
                <li>In Progress Bar output, it is now possible to use DETAILS:SHOW and DETAILS:HIDE to toggle details field visibility</li>
                <li>New feature: If script prints "QUITAPP" to STDOUT, the wrapper application will quit.</li>
                <li>Platypus now remembers app creation dialog settings such as "Optimize Nib"</li>
                <li>Platypus now remembers opened Profiles in the Open Recent menu</li>
                <li>It is now possible to add a custom MainMenu.nib to bundled files which overwrites default</li>
                <li>Extended and improved documentation</li>
                <li>Built with XCode 6, now requires Mac OS X 10.6 or later</li>
                <li>Fixed a bug where "Provide as a Service" failed to be read from saved profiles</li>
                <li>Fixed bug where a custom bundle identifier in a saved Profile would not be loaded</li>
                <li>Fixed bug where the Create button would remain greyed out even though all requirements were satisfied</li>
                <li>Fixed bug where progress indicator would keep animating after execution in Progress Bar output mode</li>
                <li>Fixed bug where command line tool complained about valid .icns filenames</li>
                <li>Fixed bug where command line tool would always create XML property lists instead of binary ones</li>
                <li>Refactored all deprecated method calls</li>
                <li>Various minor interface refinements</li>
                <li>Improved documentation</li>
                </ul>
            ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Version 4.8</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 7 Jul 2013 19:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://sveinbjorn.org/files/software/platypus/platypus4.8.zip" sparkle:version="4.8" sparkle:shortVersionString="4.8" length="1668252" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:dsaSignature="MC0CFHKG2boDHGhb2WOnsXfPRWdzbKhVAhUAhd6FcLtjnt10DaXYKfzt3dBL86s="/>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>10.5.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[
                <h2>Version 4.8 Changes</h2>
                <ul>
                    <li>New "Prompt for file on launch" option</li>
                    <li>Redesigned Drop Settings sheet</li>
                    <li>Fixed issue where version would not appear in Get Info in Finder (missing CFBundleShortVersionString)</li>
                    <li>Generated apps have NSHumanReadableCopyright defined again</li>
                    <li>Extensive updates to documentation</li>
                    <li>"Provide as a Mac OS X Service" no longer enabled by default</li>
                    <li>Removed all support for file types.  They are ancient crust now mostly ignored by Mac OS X and should no longer be used.</li>
                    <li>Improved uninstall script</li>
                    <li>Fixed issue where a generated icon file referenced in a Profile could be overwritten</li>
                    <li>Documentation files now open in default browser, not in default .html handling app</li>
                    <li>Fixed broken nib optimization. Platypus now correctly detects XCode 4 installs.</li>
                </ul>
            ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Version 4.7</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 17:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://sveinbjorn.org/files/software/platypus/platypus4.7.zip" sparkle:version="4.7" sparkle:shortVersionString="4.7" length="1838456" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:dsaSignature="MC4CFQCkcSA24nRCSW47lr6VPXMQfJOQKQIVAJo8YRI7yhKDnOjud056KdD9uNLb"/>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>10.5.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[
                <h2>Version 4.7 Changes</h2>
                <ul>
                    <li>New "Uninstall" menu option, which removes all traces of Platypus on a system</li>
                    <li>New update mechanism using the Sparkle framework and appcasting</li>
                    <li>Command line tool now supports reading script from STDIN</li>
                    <li>Command line tool now supports XML plist option </li>
                    <li>Migrated away from all deprecated Mac OS X API calls</li>
                    <li>Minor interface tweaks</li>
                    <li>Fixed bug where script permissions could be erroneously set, resulting in execution failure</li>
                    <li>Fixed bug which caused Platypus to crash when creating Droplets</li>
                    <li>Fixed bug with icon missing on "New Script" if CLI tool wasn't installed</li>
                    <li>Fixed bug with enabled an empty menu item when no profiles were in Profiles list</li>
                </ul>
            ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Version 4.6</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="http://sveinbjorn.org/files/software/platypus/platypus4.6.zip" sparkle:version="4.6" sparkle:shortVersionString="4.6" length="1455877" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:dsaSignature="MC0CFCXvwsKLXBPBT7G4u4+pCQg1cxcBAhUApHSLzNT6vPAq1zMhxLCVDMQYf68"/>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>10.5.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[
                <h2>Version 4.6 Changes</h2>
                <ul>
                    <li>"Open" and "Save" menu item option for Platypus-created apps</li>
                    <li>Applications can now be set as Services for text or file handling via Services menu</li>
                    <li>Configurable document icon for Platypus apps</li>
                    <li>New option to set custom arguments for script, not just interpreter, under "Args" (previously "Params")</li>
                    <li>Command line tool now supports dumping profile property lists to stdout (see man page)</li>
                    <li>Additional interpreter presets: zsh and tcsh</li>
                    <li>Extended documentation and FAQ</li>
                    <li>New "Edit" button and contextual menu item for Bundled Files List.</li>
                    <li>New FastDMGMounter example</li>
                    <li>Platypus now defaults to using binary-format property lists.  This can be set to XML in create panel.</li>
                    <li>Status Bar apps now gracefully remove their status bar item before exiting</li>
                    <li>Removed app path as first arg option, it's unnecessary and confusing. App path == $CWD/../..</li>
                    <li>Various interface refinements</li>
                    <li>Migrated all images to optimized PNGs for smaller file sizes</li>
                    <li>Now using LLVM for builds instead of GCC, which makes for smaller code size</li>
                    <li>Changed "New Script" preset contents to be a "Hello, World" example in the selected language</li>
                    <li>Fixed bug with script path text field tab autocomplete</li>
                    <li>Fixed bug in shell command generator which errenously inversed the logic of the -R flag</li>
                    <li>Fixed bug which caused crash when editing file in Bundled Files list using built-in editor.</li>
                    <li>Fixed bug where text font settings would not be applied</li>
                    <li>Fixed bug with contextual menus in Arguments window</li>
                    <li>Fixed bug where custom image data application icons failed to be created</li>
                    <li>Fixed bug where "Icon" display mode status item would erroneously display a default title</li>
                    <li>"Run in background" applications no longer set themselves as front process with output mode "None"</li>
                </ul>
            ]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
