<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:sparkle="http://www.andymatuschak.org/xml-namespaces/sparkle" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Platypus Version Release Appcast</title>
        <link>http://sveinbjorn.org/files/appcasts/PlatypusAppcast.xml</link>
        <description>Most recent release list for Platypus, with links to updates.</description>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title>Version 5.2</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 00:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <enclosure url="https://sveinbjorn.org/files/software/platypus/platypus5.2.zip" sparkle:version="1008" sparkle:shortVersionString="5.2" length="3649512" type="application/octet-stream" sparkle:dsaSignature="MC4CFQCt3MhvLzIQ5lRNu5d28xKXJwN7ygIVAKYgCZzZzqYfnueKlpAGI59H3ZWR"/>
            <sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>10.7.0</sparkle:minimumSystemVersion>
            <description><![CDATA[
                <h2>Version 5.2 Changes</h2>
                <ul>
                <li>Platypus apps can now register as URL scheme handlers and receive opened URLs as arguments to script</li>
                <li>Platypus apps can now accept dragged URLs</li>
                <li>Platypus apps that accept dropped files now have an Open Recent menu</li>
                <li>New syntax to create submenus in Status Menu interface type</li>
                <li>Relative paths are now supported in Platypus Profiles, but only through manual editing. Platypus app and CLT still generate Profiles with absolute paths.</li>
                <li>Platypus now warns about about identical file names in bundled files</li>
                <li>Droplet apps now quit when their window is closed</li>
                <li>Updated and improved example profiles demonstrating new features</li>
                <li>Text in Platypus apps now has a minimum font size</li>
                <li>The Platypus Profile format has changed slightly in this version, but old formats can still be read</li>
                <li>Fixed annoying issue where status menu would render before receiving all script output</li>
                <li>Fixed performance issue with printing many lines to text window. It is now very fast again.</li>
                <li>Fixed issue where loading certain Example profiles would cause Platypus to crash</li>
                <li>Fixed bug where "Use as template" was shown when Status Item mode was "Text"</li>
                <li>Fixed bug where command line tool failed to infer app name from script filename, resulting in "(null).app"</li>
                <li>Fixed bug where files that had been moved were not colored red in Bundled Files list</li>
                <li>Fixed bug where valid menu items were disabled in Action menu</li>
                <li>Fixed issue with console spamming due to missing CFBundleTypeRole. Now always "Viewer".</li>
                <li>Fixed bug where text settings were not properly loaded by the GUI</li>
                <li>Fixed bug where bundling files with the -f flag didn't work in the command line tool</li>
                <li>Fixed issue where status menu settings would not be restored to defaults on clear</li>
                <li>Fixed bug where the command line tool would erroneously try to validate whole argument strings instead of individual UTI strings</li>
                <li>Fixed bug where suffix editing buttons remained enabled when they shouldn't be</li>
                <li>Got rid of text encoding settings. Platypus now uses UTF8 for everything, and you should too.</li>
                <li>Got rid of "Secure bundled script" option, which was useless bullshit anyway</li>
                <li>Fixed issue where main application window would not remember its last position</li>
                <li>Updated documentation & man page</li>
                <li>Various minor interface refinements</li>
                </ul>
            ]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
